ESMOND ABBAN

Computer Systems Manager



+233 59736 2178

esmondabban3@gmail.com



Accra, Dansoman 233

Career objective

A Motivated Computer Technician with a 4+ years extensive knowledge of Web Development, Design, Networking and Programming, as well as experience in a wide range of programming languages, frameworks, and tools. Proven success in developing and deploying applications, websites, and web service. I am a motivated professional who offers expertise in programming languages like python, C++, JavaScript and HTML.

experience

Jan 2023 - Present

WEB DEVELOPER

Npuntu Technologies, Accra, Dansoman

- My job description allows me to identify and communicate technical problems, processes and come up with solutions to aid in the flow of the Website.
- I write, modify, integrate and test software code for e-commerce and other internet applications.
- I also maintain existing computer programs by making modifications as required.

Mar 2021 - Nov 2022

NETWORK SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

United WorldNet System, Accra, Dansoman

- I Install, maintain, troubleshoot and upgrade Web-server hardware and software
- I Implement data, software and hardware security procedures
- I provide problem-solving services to network users
- Verifies and logs receipt of data.
- Transfers information from paper formats into computer files using keyboards, data recorders, or optical scanners.

education

Feb 2023

COURSE IN PROGRAMMING AND WEB DEVELOPMENT

AQskill, Online Course

Nov 2022

COURSE IN WEB DEVELOPMENT

Webbiit Technologies, Online Course

Mar 2019

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MANAGEMENT WITH COMPUTING

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and technology, Kumasi

Awards & Honors

Second Class Honours (Upper Division)

experience

Jun 2019 – Jun 2021

WEB & GRAPHIC DESIGN

Entsiey System Design and Development, Akotsi, Central Region

- I come up with the sketch concept and layout design and then communicate with the client for their approval, before I begin with the deign
- Managed design team of four that developed large scale print project with 100 pieces for retail.
- I come up with the sketch concept and layout design and then communicate with the client for their approval, before I begin with the deign
- Designed user centric website interfaces using HTML CSS and JAVASCRIPT.
- Conceived UI design from inception to the final product and successfully launched a brand new website for growth.
- Developed new mock ups and specifications.

skills

- PHP
- Web Security
- MySQL, SQL
- Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- CorelDraw
- Mobile Application Development
- React.js
- Adobe InDesign
- HTML CSS

- Project Management
- Written and Oral Communications
- Attention to Detail
- Technical Support
- Bootstrap Framework
- Python
- Graphic and User Interface Design
- JavaScript
- MS Word
- Hardware and Networking

certifications

Bachelor of Science Certificate

• Certificate in Web Development